Let's code up a simple blue screen color selection in Python.
我们来在 Python 里编写一段代码吧 用这段代码来进行简单的蓝幕颜色选择
We'll be using a new library in this lesson called OpenCV,
本课我们要用一个新库 叫做 OpenCV
which is commonly used in
该库常用于计算机视觉应用
computer vision applications and will help us create custom applications of our own.
能帮我们开发自定义应用程序
We'll be starting with an image of a pizza on a blue screen background.
我们有张以蓝幕为背景的披萨图
We'll first have to identify this blue region,
我们要先把这个蓝色区域识别出来
then later we'll replace it with a background image of our choosing.
然后再将它替换成我们选择的背景图片
Here's our Python notebook and my first step is to
这是我们的 Python notebook
import the libraries I need and we'll use these throughout this lesson.
第一步 导入要用的库 我们整个课程都会用到这些库
For plotting I'll import pyplot from matplotlib and for operating on
从 matplotlib 导入 pyplot 来绘图
an image I'll use numpy and the computer vision library OpenCV which is named cv2.
至于图像处理 则用 numpy 和计算机视觉库 OpenCV 该库名为 cv2
Next, I'll read in the image of the pizza using cv2.imread.
接着 用 cv2.imread 来读取披萨图
The image is named pizza_ bluescreen.jpg
图像名为 pizza_ bluescreen.jpg
and it's in the same directory as this notebook in a folder named "images".
该图所在目录与这个 notebook 一样 都是在名为 “images” 的文件夹里
Once it's read in, you may want to print out some information about the image.
读取完毕后 你可能想输出一些图像信息
This is often helpful to see before starting to manipulate any image.
在处理任何图像之前 先看看这些信息总是很有帮助的
So I'll print out what type of data it is and I expect it to be a 2D array,
所以我要输出数据的类型 我想这应该是个二维数组
also known as a grid or matrix of pixel values.
也就是一个储存着像素值的网格或矩阵
And I'll also print its shape which will tell us the dimensions of the image.
我还要输出形状 以便了解图像的维数
Then let's run this and we see the expected output.
运行这段代码 我们就看到了预料之中的输出
The image is indeed an array and its shape contains
这张图像的确是个数组 其形状包含了三个值
three values that represent the dimensions of the image array.
代表了图像数组的不同维度
First its height 514 pixels,
第一个是高度 514 像素
then its width 816,
然后是宽度 816
and finally how many color components it has: in this case three,
最后是颜色分量的数目 这里有三种
for red, green and blue values.
即红色、绿色和蓝色的值
Next I'll display this image using pyplot.
接着 用 pyplot 把图像显示出来
But we can see that the image looks weird,
可图像看起来怪怪的
that the background is red and not blue like we expect.
背景是红色的 而不是我们预料的蓝色
So what's happening here?
这是为什么呢？
Well, OpenCV reads in color images as BGR (blue,
这是因为 OpenCV 会把彩色图像读取成 BGR (蓝、绿、红) 图像
green, red) images and not RGB.
而不是 RGB 图像
So the red and blue colors are in reverse order and pyplot reflects this switch.
所以红色和蓝色掉转过来了 而 pyplot 呈现的就是调转后的图像
You can learn more about why OpenCV does this in text.
至于 OpenCV 这么读取的原因 请见文本说明
But for this and many other examples I'll often change
但我会把这张图从 BGR 转为 RGB
images from BGR to RGB because they'll will be easier to display.
这样才方便展示 以后还有很多例子我也会这么做
So before we display the image let's make a copy of
所以在显示图像之前 先复制原始图像
the original image and use OpenCV to change the color from BGR to RGB.
用 OpenCV 将颜色从 BGR 改为 RGB
It's good practice to always make a copy of the image you're working with.
处理图像时 顺手备份是个好习惯
This way any transformation you'll apply to the copy will not affect the original image,
这样一来 无论你对副本进行什么变换 原图都不会受到影响
so it's easier to undo a step or try something new.
这样要撤回操作或尝试新方法都容易许多
And I'll name this copy image_copy.
我把这个副本命名为 image_copy
Then on this copy we can perform
然后
a color transformation using the OpenCV function cvtColor.
我们就可以用 OpenCV 的函数 cvtColor 对副本进行颜色转换了
This takes in a source image and
该函数需要输入的参数有源图像
color conversion code which in this case is just BGR to RGB,
和颜色转换代码 这里的代码即 BGR2RGB
and then outputs the desired image.
然后输出我们想要的图像
Then if we plot this image copy we see the blue screen background as expected.
这回如果把图像副本绘制出来 我们就能如愿以偿地看到蓝幕背景了
I went through this image reading,
刚才我放慢速度给大家演示了图像读取和复制
copying and displaying code fairly slowly this time,
也给大家看了代码
because we'll be using it regularly.
因为这些是常用步骤
But now let's jump into the blue screen color threshold code.
现在我们开始来讲蓝幕颜色阀值的代码
To create a color threshold,
要创建颜色阀值
I'll first define lower and upper bounds for the color I want to isolate - blue.
首先得定义要分离的颜色的上下限 也就是蓝色的上下限
I want to use these values to eventually select
我想用这些值
the blue screen area that contains this range of color values and get rid of it.
选出包含这个颜色值范围的蓝幕区域 然后将该区域删除
So I'll define a lower threshold that contains the lowest values of red,
我要定义下限 下限涉及的红、
green and blue that are still considered part of the blue screen background.
绿和蓝三者的值就是仍能视为蓝幕背景的最小值
This will be an array of three values.
所以这会是个包含三个值的数组
For red and green, I'll set this as 0 meaning it's okay to have no red or green.
我把红色和绿色的值设为 0 意味着就算没有红色和绿色也行
But the lowest value for blue should still be quite high.
但蓝色就算是最小值也要设得高些
Now all the way up to 255,
虽然不至于要 255 那么高
but let's say around 230.
但也得设在 230 左右吧
Similarly, I'll define the upper threshold.
上限也是一个原理
I'll define it to allow a little more red and green,
这次允许红色和绿色的值多一点
say 50 each, and I'll set the highest value for blue to be 255.
就设两者都为 50  吧 然后把蓝色的最大值设为 255
Any color within this low and high range will be an intense blue color.
任何在这个上下限范围里的值都会是明显的蓝色
I'm doing some estimation though so if I find that
不过我只是估算了一下
this range isn't finding the blue screen area that I want,
所以如果在这个范围里找不到我要的蓝幕区域
I'll come back and change these values.
那我就会回到这一步 修改这些值
Next, I'll use the color bounds I just created to create an image mask.
接下来 我要用刚才创建的颜色阀值来创建图像掩膜
Masks are a very common way to isolate
掩膜常用于
a selected area of interest and do something with that area.
把我们选定的感兴趣区域分离出来 以便进行操作
We can create a mask over the blue area using OpenCVs in inRange function.
我们可以用 OpenCV 的函数 inRange 在蓝色区域上覆盖一层掩膜
This function takes in an image in
该函数需要输入的参数有
our lower and upper color bounds and defines a mask by asking if
图像、颜色的上限和下限
the color value of each image pixel falls
定义掩膜时 函数会确认各图像像素的颜色值
in the range of the lower and upper color thresholds.
是否在颜色阀值的范围内
If it does fall in this range,
如果在
the mask will allow it to be displayed and
那掩膜就会把像素显示出来
if not it will block it out and turn the pixel back.
如果不在 掩膜就会遮住像素 把像素变成黑色
In fact, we can visualize the mask by plotting it as we would an image.
事实上 我们可以跟绘制图像一样 将掩膜可视化
This white area is where the image will be allowed to
白色区域是图像可以透过掩膜显示出来的部分
show through and the black will be blocked out.
黑色则是会被掩膜遮住的部分
In numerical values, we can look at this mask as
从值上看 我们可以把这个掩膜
a 2D grid with the same dimensions as our image;
看成一个二维网格 其维度和我们的图像相同
514 pixels in height and 816 in width.
高度为 514 像素 宽度为 816
And each coordinate in this mask has a value of either 255 for white or 0 for black,
掩膜的每个坐标都有一个代表白色的值 255 或代表黑色的值 0
sort of like a grayscale image.
有点像灰度图像
And when we look at this mask we can see that it has a white area where
观察这个掩膜 我们可以发现它有个区域是白色的
the blue screen background is and a black area where the pizza is.
这是蓝幕背景所在之处 还有个区域是黑色的 这是披萨所在之处
And the first thing we want to do is let
所以首先
the pizza show through and block the blue screen background.
我们要把披萨显示出来 同时遮住蓝幕背景
First, to mask the image I'll make another image copy
首先 给图像添加掩膜 我再复制一次图像
called masked image of our color changed image copy,
将其命名为 masked image 意思是颜色转换后的掩膜副本图像
just in case I want to change the mask later on.
如果我稍后想修改掩膜 这样会方便些
Then one way to select the blue screen area is by asking for the part of
要选择蓝幕区域 一个办法是
that image that overlaps with the part of the mask that is white or not black.
提取图像与掩膜白色区域重叠的部分 或者说是与掩膜非黑区域重叠的部分
That is, we'll select the part of the image where
也就是说 我们要选择的那部分图像
the area of the mask is not equal to zero,
是掩膜不等于 0 的区域
using this exclamation point equals boolean operator,
所以要用 “！=” 这个布尔操作符
where the exclamation point means not.
其中感叹号的意思是 “非”
And to block this background area out we then set these pixels to black.
要把这个背景遮住 我们得把这些像素设为黑色
In RGB black is just zeros for all three color values.
在 RGB 里 黑色就是三个颜色值都为 0
Then when we display our image we should see that
把图像显示出来 我们应该就能看到
the pizza area is the only area that shows through;
披萨是唯一显示出来的部分
the blue screen background is gone.
而蓝幕背景已经消失了
I might even change my color thresholds to get rid of these last few spots.
甚至我还可以修改颜色阀值 把剩下的这些小点去掉
I'll try increasing my highest green value to 70 and decreasing my low blue value to 220.
我试着将绿色的最大值调到 70 将蓝色的最小值调到 220
This should capture a larger range of blue.
这样能获取的蓝色范围应该就更广了
Then I'll run the masking and displaying code again.
再次运行掩膜和图像显示代码
And this image looks even better.
效果更好了
Now we just have one last step which is to apply a background to this image.
现在就剩最后一步了 也即给这张图像添加背景
The process will be fairly similar so I'll go through these steps fairly quickly.
操作很类似 所以我就快速过一遍了
First, I'll read in an image of outer space and convert it to RGB color.
首先 读取一张外太空的图像 将其转为 RGB 颜色
I'll also crop it so that it's the same size as our pizza image;
裁剪图像 使其与披萨图大小相同
514 by 816 pixels.
也即 514 乘 816 像素
I'm calling this image crop_background.
将其命名为 crop_background
Then I'll apply the mask,
然后应用掩膜
this time using the opposite mask,
这次要用的掩膜完全相反
meaning I want the background to show through and not the Pizza area.
也就是说得让背景显示出来 而不显示披萨所在的区域
If we look back at the mask in this case I'm blocking
如果重新回来看这个掩膜 我们就能发现
the part of the background image where the mask is equal to zero.
这次我遮住的是图像背景 也就是掩膜的值等于 0 的部分
And for this we say mask == 0.
所以写 mask == 0
Just to make sure I got this masking correct,
为了确认掩膜是否正确
I'll plot the resulting image and I get the background with the pizza cut out.
我把操作后的图像绘制出来 于是看到了没有披萨的背景
Then finally I just need to add these two images together.
确认完毕 最后只需将两张图像叠放到一起
Since the black area is equivalent to zeros in pixel color value,
因为黑色区域的像素颜色值等于 0
a simple addition will work.
所以我们只需进行简单的加法
And when I plot the complete image I get a pizza floating in space. And that's it.
绘制出整张图像 披萨就漂浮在天空里了 就是这样
In text you'll find notes on the functions we use to get here.
你可以在文本里查看函数注释
And next you'll get some hands on practice coding your own color threshold.
接下来你需要做些练习 动手编写自己的颜色阀值代码